A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Catalogued Reports, Reports 9287-11774 FA739D
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Exchange rate strategies and real adjustment after the oil price shocks: the experience of the smaller European economies (Reports 011760-013), 1985 (Box 528)
- Meeting the needs and potential of informal firms through microenterprise promotion, 1985 (Reports 011761) (Box 528)
  Based in part upon research done by Stearns as an intern and consultant for the Rural Poverty and Resources program of the Ford Foundation. Includes bibliographical references (p. 105-111). This is an expanded and substantially different version of Report
- Interaction of health technology and social organization: the Takemi lecture, Harvard School of Public Health (Reports 011762), 1984 (Box 528)
  Discusses impact of health care intervention on child mortality, based upon research conducted by the International Centre for Diarrheal Disease Research, Bangladesh (ICDDR,B) in Matlab Thana. Includes statistical tables.
  22, 12 leaves.
  Children -- Mortality; Child health services -- Developing countries; Child health services -- Research -- Bangladesh -- Matlab Thana
- The role of a private philanthropy in India (Reports 011763), 1984 (Box 528)
  Lecture presented to the Delhi chapter of the Society for International Development on Sept. 14, 1984. Discusses the history of and rationale for Ford Foundation involvement in India.
  Technical assistance -- India
- Middle East program: discussion paper (Reports 011764), 1973 (Box 528)
  Discusses conditions in the Middle East, the objectives of the Ford Foundation's program there, and program strategies.
  Social sciences -- Arab countries; Technical assistance -- Middle East
- Ford Foundation history project (Reports 011765), 1985 (Box 528, Reel R-9302)
  This report contains Sections II and III of the projected study. Reports #011012 contains draft of Section I and chapters on the Ford Foundation in Turkey and Nepal.
  Overseas development: part II
- Trip report, 1987 Sept.-Oct. (Reports 011766) (Box 528)
  Report on a trip to South Africa to collect data for the Information Exchange, "A U.S.-South African cooperative program to expand educational opportunities for black South Africans." -letterhead. The Information Exchange is under the auspices of the Inst
  08601048
  95 leaves.
  Education -- Research -- South Africa; Politics and education -- South Africa; Blacks -- Education -- South Africa
- Public impressions of the Ford Foundation in the United States (Reports 011767), 1987 (Box 528)
  Memorandum to the President and Board of Trustees, dated September 10, 1987.
- Significant features of the South African context (Reports 011768), 1987 (Box 528)
  Apartheid -- South Africa; Human rights -- South Africa; Political science -- South Africa
- Visit to South Africa (Reports 011769), 1978 (Box 528)
  File memo dated January 10, 1978.
  42 leaves + attachment -- 28 cm.
  Apartheid -- South Africa; Political science -- South Africa; Human rights -- South Africa; Technical assistance -- South Africa; Endowments -- South Africa -- Evaluation
- A study of detention and torture in South Africa: preliminary report, 1985 Sept. (Reports 011770) (Box 528)
  08351051
  iv, 61 leaves.
  Detention of persons -- South Africa; Torture -- South Africa
- Politics and crisis: reflections on the state of the Western Cape 1981-1987 (Reports 011771) (Box 529)
  36 leaves -- 28 cm.
- Physical and mental effects of unemployment on individuals and their families: report to the Ford Foundation 1977? (Reports 011772) (Box 529)
  07490810
  Unemployment -- Psychological aspects; Unemployment -- Social aspects
- Information papers on South Africa and Namibia and Human Rights and Governance Programs (Reports 011773), 1990 (Box 529)
  Two information papers prepared for the June 1990 meeting of the Board of Trustees, June 27, 1990.
  Developing Countries Program/Eastern & Southern Africa; United States and International Affairs Program/Human Rights and Governance; Board of Trustees
  var. pag.: ill., tables, charts -- 28 cm.
  Human Rights and Governance program: site visits, Board of Trustees meeting, the Ford Foundation, June 28, 1990; Overview of program: South Africa and Namibia, Board of Trustees meeting, the Ford Foundation, June 27, 1990
  Human rights; Social justice; Political planning
- Project reports, 1971-1973. (Reports 011774)
  Contains preliminary reports produced by PPNP on education in Indonesia: preschool education (by S. Darmadji), primary education (by C.E. Beeby), alternative courses of action in secondary education (by C.E. Beeby), and higher education (by Richard Pearse
  06900269; 07200222.
  1 archives box containing 6 volumes (5 linear inches).
  Preschool education in Indonesia: progress report 1969-1971; Primary education; Secondary education, part c: alternative courses of action; Secondary education. part c, section 14-14:58: strategies for introducing change; Higher education in Indonesia; Perm
  Educational surveys -- Indonesia; Education -- Research -- Indonesia; Educational evaluation -- Indonesia; Educational planning -- Indonesia; Education, Preschool -- Indonesia; Education, Primary -- Indonesia; Education, Secondary -- Indonesia; Education, Higher
- Preschool Education in Indonesia: Progress Report, 1969 (Reports 011774-001), 1971 (Box 529)
  06900269; 07200222
- Trial Report Level III: Chapter on Primary Education (Reports 011774-002), 1971 (Box 529)
- Chapter VI: Level III Report: Secondary Education, Part C, Alternative Courses of Action (Reports 011774-003), 1972 (Box 529)
- Chapter VI: Secondary Education, Part C, Section 14-14-58: Strategies for Introducing Changes (Reports 011774-004), 1972 (Box 529)
- Level II Report: Higher Education in Indonesia (Reports 011774-005), 1973 (Box 529)
- Permanency of Literacy (Reports 011774-006), 1971 (Box 529)